<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cicd on Benjamin Muschko&#39;s development blog</title>
    <link>https://bmuschko.com/tags/cicd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cicd on Benjamin Muschko&#39;s development blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bmuschko.com/tags/cicd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Groovy with Bazel</title>
      <link>https://bmuschko.com/blog/bazel-groovy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bmuschko.com/blog/bazel-groovy/</guid>
      <description>Bazel is a build automation tool that ships with support for a variety of languages out-of-the-box. For example, you can build Java projects right away without having to configure external functionality, so-called rules. Groovy is a popular language in the JVM space. As a developer, you’d expect the following features:
   Compiling Groovy source code
  Creating a JAR file to bundle the class files
  Executing Groovy-based tests written with JUnit or Spock</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best practices for writing Jenkins shared libraries</title>
      <link>https://bmuschko.com/blog/jenkins-shared-libraries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bmuschko.com/blog/jenkins-shared-libraries/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Pipeline definitions in Jenkins start small and maintainble. You write a Jenkinsfile that declares a couple of stages. Nothing dramatic, simple, understandable code. As your adoption of Jenkins and &amp;#34;pipelines as code&amp;#34; grows within the organization, you’ll find out that other teams are copy-pasting pipeline code all over the place. What works for one project should work for other projects, right?! Soon requirements become more complex and your organization will enter a world of pain of unmaintainable, duplicated code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
